全部带走 弟兄们
Take it all, men!
一个子儿都别剩
Leave nothing behind!
晚上好 朋友
Good evening, my dear fellow.
我和弟兄们要去皇宫 能拜托你引个路吗
Would you be kind enough to escort my men and I to the palace?
这是什么意思
What is the meaning of this?
我的王
This, my good king,
这是将被载入英联邦史册的辉煌壮举
is going to be remembered in your delightful commonwealth.
因为今晚 你们将接待七大洋中
For tonight, you will be host to the most brutal of scoundrels
最残暴的恶棍
the seven seas has ever encountered.
拿下
Guard him.
慢慢来 先生们
Take your time, gents.
好东西多的是 人人有份
Plenty of swag for everyone.
小模样挺俊
That's a smart look, chum.
不介意的话 把佩剑交出来
Your order, if you don't mind.
女士 这是什么迷人香味
Ah, me lady. What is that delightful fragrance?
这叫沐浴
It's called a bath.
有机会你也该试试
You should try it sometime.
唐突了
Pardon me for being so bold.
现在 能麻烦你把国库的钥匙给我吗
Now, then, can I trouble you for the keys to the Treasury?
国库里 各种各样的金银珠宝和货币
Inside that vault was almost $3 million
总价值约达300万美元
in gold, silver and currency,
我们全部拿走了
and we took it all.
那天晚上
That night,
皇宫 国库
the Royal Palace, the Treasury
还有岛上所有的名门望族
and all the large island companies
都被我们按计划掠夺一空
were systematically plundered.
海盗是正在消亡的一类人
We were a dying breed,
我们是七大洋上的最后一支了
the last remaining corsairs on the seven seas.
但是瓦胡岛之行 将成为海盗一族最伟大的胜利
But the island of Oahu would be our greatest pillage.
女士们 先生们 晚上好
Aloha ahiahi. Ladies and gentlemen,
我美丽的妹妹科诺
my beautiful cousin Kono has given me the duty
邀请我今晚为大家演唱
and makana of being your entertainment for tonight.
但是首先 让我们以热烈的掌声欢迎新郎新娘出场
But first I'd like you all to give it up for the bride and groom.
他们就是
Here they are for the very first time.
西村先生和西村女士
Mr. And Mrs. Noshimuri.
借过一下 女士 发生了什么
Excuse me, Ma'am. So what happened?
加布里埃尔在停车场拿枪指着我
Gabriel pulled a gun on me in the parking lot.
我改主意了
I've changed my mind.
我不打算走了
No longer planning on leaving.
你跟你朋友
It's only a matter of time
迟早会再挡我的道
before you and your friends get in my way again.
所以我来跟你做个交易
So I've come to offer you a deal.
是吗
Really?
50%的毒品帝国
50% of his growing drug
看来出价很大方
empire seems like a pretty generous offer.
那你怎么说
So what'd you say?
我劝他最好还是开枪
I told him he'd better pull the trigger,
不然我早晚会找到他然后扳倒他
because if he didn't, I would find him and put him down.
等等
Okay, wait a minute.
这家伙来你妹妹的婚礼上找你
This guy comes at you at your cousin's wedding,
他知道我们都在这儿
he knows we're all here.
他不是想收买我们
This is not about a bribe.
他是在给我们传递一个信息
He's trying to send us a message.
对 他想说他一点儿也不忌惮我们
Yeah, and the message is saying he ain't scared of us.
伙伴们 我不是低估这件事情的严重性
Guys, look, I don't mean to downplay how serious this was,
只是 想想我们现在在哪儿
but... let's remember why we're here
你说的很对
You know what? You're absolutely right.
没错 这是科诺和亚当的婚礼
Yes, she is. This is Kono and Adam's night--
我们应该和他们一起庆祝
we should be celebrating with them.
这样的话 我要去找我的女王陛下
Well, in that case, I better go find Her Majesty
一起跳舞了
and get my dance on.
我去找格蕾丝跳舞
I'm gonna dance with Grace.
你呢 探长
What about you, sailor?
你行吗
You still got it?
当然
Oh, yeah, I still got it.
你呢
You still got it?
走吧 舞林高手
Let's go, hotshot.
放马过来
Bring it!
你来吗
You coming?
你们年轻人先去玩吧 我一会儿就来
You kids go have fun. I'll catch up with you.
格罗佛夫人
Mrs. Grover?
来吗
Are we going?
当然了
Yeah, we're going.
够久了
Took you long enough.
跳舞吗
Let's dance.
我不确定
I don't know.
我现在膝盖有点软
I'm a little weak in the knees right now.
- 真的吗  - 是啊
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
走吧
Come on.
哥 来吧 一起跳
Hey, cuz, come on, let me see those moves.
当然
Absolutely.
你好
Hello.
不 我醒了
No, I'm awake.
好 我马上就到
Yeah, I'll be right there.
真是个不一般的夜晚
That was some night.
是啊 意义重大
Yeah, it was pretty epic.
我本来希望
I was kind of hoping you and I
今天早上能跟你聊一会儿
could talk a little bit this morning.
晚点聊
We will.
去吧 我等你回来
Go. Go. I'll be here when you get back.
受害者名叫基努・卡森
Vic's name is Keanu Carson.
40岁 独居
40 years old, lives alone.
除此之外呢 杜克
What else do we know about this guy, Duke?
没有犯罪记录 邻居说他很友善
No record. Neighbors say he was friendly.
有个女朋友 伊莎贝尔・拉农
He had a girlfriend, Isabelle Lono.
我们正在找她
We're trying to track her down.
他还写书
Also, he wrote books.
机场小说
Airport fiction.
哇哦 看这个
Whoa, look at this.
- 这是什么  - 录像带
- What is it? - Videocassettes.
你上次看到这种东西是什么时候了
When was the last time you saw one of these?
我忘了 而且都是自制的
I don't know. It's all homemade stuff.
有一盘不见了
Except there's one missing.
拜伦・沃什伯恩采访记录 1975年10月
Byron Washburn Interview. October 1975.
丹尼 看那儿
Danny, look at that.
所以卡森先生正在看
All right, so Mr. Carson here is watching
拜伦・沃什伯恩1975年的采访记录
Byron Washburn interview from 1975.
也许凶手走的时候带走了这盘录像带
Maybe the killer takes the tape with him when he leaves.
就在他对被害人开枪之后
Right after he puts a bullet in this guy.
- 不过拜伦・沃什伯恩是谁  - 我不清楚
- But who's Byron Washburn? - I don't know.
可能受害人正在写一部关于他的机场小说
Maybe this guy is writing a airport novel about him.
如果是这样的话 看来有第三者
If that's the case, it looks like there's somebody out there
不希望这个故事公之于众
who doesn't want that story told.
好了 睁开眼睛
All right, open up.
你做的吗
You made this?
别这么惊讶
Don't look so surprised.
你通常都需要帮忙
Well, you've always had help.
那么 是时候改变了
Well, that's about to change.
我是认真的 亚当
I meant what I said, Adam.
这些都不重要
None of this matters.
我只想要你
I only want you.
过来
So come here.
早餐要冷了
It's getting cold.
尝尝
Try it.
你一直煮得这么好吃的话 我会马上发胖的
You keep cooking like this, I'll be fat in no time.
我喜欢你变胖
I think I like you fat.
你说什么
What are you saying?
我说
I am saying
有一天
someday
我想跟你有一个家庭
I'd like to have a family with you.
西村夫人
Mrs. Noshimuri.
我也希望
I think I like that.
卡拉卡瓦先生
Mr. Kalakaua.
好吧 我该改成你的姓了 是吗 过来
OK. I am supposed to take your last name. Is that it? Here.
我去开门
I gotta do it.
马上回来
Be right back.
来了
Just a sec.
快递 西村夫妇
Delivery. Mr. And Mrs. Noshimuri.
好的 好大的礼物
Alright. What a gift.
亚当
Adam.
现场组检查了基努・卡森家
So, CSU Processed Keanu Carson's house.
没有嫌疑人的痕迹 不过我们在努力找
It was clean, but we did manage to get a lead on the name
遗失的VHS制式录像带上的名字
from the missing VHS tape.
拜伦・沃什伯恩 对吧
Byron Washburn, right?
Beta
Beta.
- 什么  - 那是Beta制式录像带的盒子 不是VHS制式的
- Excuse me? - What is a box for a betamax tape, not VHS.
实际上 VHS制式录像带的尺寸要比Beta制式的大8%
VHS is actually eight percent larger than betas.
顺便提一句 VHR各方面都不如Beta
Incidentally, they were inferior in every way.
Beta制式的录像带画质也更好 音质也更好
Beta had better picture, better sound.
不过因为一些原因
But for some reason,
这种格式一直没在普罗大众中流行起来
the format never caught on with the general public.
那也是一个阴谋吗
Is that a conspiracy, too?
不 只是一场基本格式大战
No. Just a basic format war.
不是所有事情都是阴谋
Not everything's a conspiracy.
我看好你 他怎么在这儿
I like you. Why is he here?
因为科诺在休蜜月假
Oh, with Kono off on her honeymoon,
所以我让杰瑞来帮忙
I asked Jerry to pitch in.
他能提供我们需要的一切帮助
Think we're gonna need all the help we can get on this one.
- 很高兴你能加入 杰瑞  - 不客气
- Glad to have you, Jer. - You're welcome.
很好 所以我们能继续谈沃什伯恩了吗
Okay, so, can we, uh... Can we get back to Washburn?
他的名字曾在1975年
So, the guy's name appears
出现在一家出版社的新闻稿上
on a publisher's press release from back in 1975.
报道显示当地一个名叫南森・埃克斯利博士的历史老师
Seems a local history teacher named Dr. Nathan Exley
当时正在写一本有关海盗的书
was writing a book about a band of pirates operating
这群海盗曾在19世纪80年代早期在太平洋上出没
in the Pacific during the early 1880s,
沃什伯恩是这群海盗中最后的幸存者
and Washburn was the last surviving member of the crew.
19世纪80年代还有海盗
Still had pirates in the 1880s?
其实我记得我听说过这帮人
Actually, you know, I remember hearing about these guys.
我小时候
When I was a kid,
我叔叔曾经给我讲过一个睡前故事
my uncle used to tell me a bedtime story
说的是这群海盗半夜袭击瓦胡岛
about this crew launching a midnight raid on O'Ahu.
传说他们曾包围全岛数小时
Legend has it that they laid siege to the island for hours
最后带着价值几百万的宝物逃跑了
before escaping with a treasure worth millions.
最后一票了 兄弟们
It's a fine haul, gents.
绝对是最后一票了
Fine haul indeed.
当然了只是传说
Of course that's just folklore.
几乎没人相信他们真的到过这里
Hardly anyone believes that they actually were here.
不过当时
But back in the day,
这群海盗确实袭击过几十个岛
These pirates actually did hit dozens of islands,
而且靠这样搜刮了一大笔财富
and they amassed a huge treasure.
报道上还说
The press release also says
南森・埃克斯利录了关于沃什伯恩的一系列录像
that Nathan Exley conducted a series of video interviews
沃什伯恩当时已经104岁了
with Washburn, who at the time was 104 years old.
传说中提到的大多数珍宝至今还没被找到
Most of this treasure wasn't recovered,
所以我们有理由假设 其中很多仍然流落在外
so it's safe to assume a lot of it's still out there.
也许 沃什伯恩在这盘录像带中
Maybe Washburn, on this tape,
提到了如何找到剩余的财宝
said something that could lead to the rest of it.
这样的话
Okay, well, that would
有点凉了 不过还是很好吃哒
A bit luke, still tasty.
不用 谢谢了 杰瑞
No, I don't. Thank you. Um, Jerry,
我不想没礼貌
I don't mean to be rude,
可是你一定要在我办公室里
but do you have to work in my office,
用我的东西 来做事吗
at my desk... with my stuff?
如果你肯给我一间办公室的话 我就不会在这儿了
Not if you gave me an office.
好吧 我考虑一下
Okay. I'll consider it.
怎么样 好吧
- How about that? - Okay.
但是不要考虑太久 我还有得选的
But don't take too long. I do have options.
好的
Noted.
你有什么线索吗
Do you have something for me in all this?
你知道有句俗语叫
Hey, you know the old saying
椰子不会落到离树很远的地方
that the coconut doesn't fall far from the tree?
我很确定那是苹果 但请你继续
I'm pretty sure it's "Apple," But go on.
管它怎么说吧
Okay, whatever.
但是你们要找的这个女人 辛迪・帕特森
But that woman you're looking for, Cindy Patterson,
原来她不只是一名现代海盗
it turns out that not only is she a modern-day pirate,
她还是一名海盗的孙女
she's the descendant of one.
这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
她母亲的姓氏是沃什本
Her mother's maiden name was Washburn.
- 就是  - 就是
-As in... - As in
拜伦・沃什本的沃什本
Byron Washburn.
她在辛迪出生之前
She had it legally changed to Patterson
- 已经改名了  - 成
- before Cindy was born. - Chin.
她可能不想要
Probably to distance herself
这笔不义的遗产
from the legacy of a murderous pirate.
- 这线索不错  - 怎么了
- This is good. - What's up?
听这个
All right, check it out.
辛迪帕特森是沃什本的曾外孙女
Cindy Patterson is Washburn's great-granddaughter.
龙生龙 凤生凤
Apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
就跟我说的一样
Exactly what I said.
卡尔森在拍卖会买下了艾斯利的研究资料
Okay, so Carson buys Exley's research at auction,
发现了沃什本的采访
discovers the Washburn interview,
并且联系了他家人想要他们过来看一下
and contacts the man's family to offer them a look,
一般好人都会这么做
which is what a nice guy would do.
他是在知道这宝藏之前
He makes this call before he learns
就已经打了电话
about the buried treasure,
这样他已经将他自己置身于危险之中
at which point he's already put himself in danger.
是不是很刺激
Doesn't this blow your mind?
你们的嫌疑人竟然是一名21世纪的安妮・伯妮
Your suspect is a 21st century Anne Bonny.
这是有多酷炫啊
How cool is that?
但是这个安妮杀人了
Except for the part where she kills a guy.
是的 没错
Yeah, except that part.
我调查了辛迪・帕特森的曾外祖父的背景
And I did some background on Cindy Patterson's great-granddad.
在40年代的时候他在宫廷里干了几年活
It turns out that he was on staff here at the palace
不过被解雇了
for a few years in the '40s, but he got canned.
- 为什么  - 不清楚
- What for? - Not sure.
我再去调查下以前的员工记录
I'm gonna do some digging in some old employee records,
看有没有发现 不过
see what I can find out. But...
我觉得他家人已经发现了他过去是一名海盗
I'm thinking folks discovered that he had been a pirate.
大伙儿 有发现 过来看看
Hey, guys, I got something. Come on.
干得不错 杰瑞
Good work, Jerry.
我刚刚跟交通安全管理局的人联系
So, I just got off with TSA.
他们说辛迪帕特森两天前在佛罗里达
They told me that cindy patterson flew here
买了一张到夏威夷的单程票
two days ago on a one-way ticket from Florida.
而且她还和这人一起飞过来
She was traveling with this guy.
是不是有点眼熟
Notice any resemblance?
都是同一个人
Same guy.
他叫赛门・摩尔
Simon Moore's his name.
- 我们对这人有什么了解  - 并不多
- What do we know about him? - Not much.
但是我查了他的信用卡资料
But I checked with his credit card companies.
他一到这里就租了40英尺长的帆船
As soon as he got into town, he rented a 40-foot sailboat.
他们肯定是用那艘船计划将
That boat's got to be how they're planning
宝藏带出夏威夷
to get the treasure off the island.
想从你们俩身上得到答案就像拔掉牙齿那样
Getting answers out of you two is like pulling teeth.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
那招还蛮损的
That was in poor taste.
但是可以结束
This can end.
你只需要给我密码就可以了
All you got to do is give me the passcodes.
不
No.
不 不要
No, don't do it!
你新娘简直是一名女汉子
Your bride, she's one tough lady.
有什么要说吗
Something to say?
行了 好吧 你赢了
Okay! Okay, you win.
我会给你想要的
I'll give you what you want.
只是不要再碰她
Just don't touch her again.
不 不要
No, don't do it!
到你了
Your turn.
- 不要给他 亚当  - 把密码告诉戴门
- No, Adam, no. - Give Damon the codes.
亚当 不要给
Adam, no.
密码是没用的
The codes are useless.
我向银行做了明确的指示
I made specific instructions with my bank.
转账只能由我亲自操作
The transfer can only be initiated in person.
亚当 如果你骗我的话
Adam, if you're lying to me...
她必死无疑
She's gonna die.
慢慢地死去
Very slowly.
而且我还会让你看着
And I'm gonna make you watch.
- 明白吗  - 知道了
- You understand? - Yeah.
我知道了
I understand.
- 没人  - 没人
- Clear. - Clear.
没人
Clear.
他们可能还没找到宝藏
Maybe they haven't recovered the treasure yet.
又或者他们已经找到了 并且用别的途径转移了
Or they have and they're moving it some other way.
成 那是什么
Chin, what's that?
这么宝贵还藏在这里也是醉了
So much for it being priceless.
他们把画框给拿掉了
They ripped the frame off this thing.
里面一定有什么
There must have been something inside.
可能线索在油画里面
Could've been some clue on the canvas
又或许是其中一个镶边
or maybe one of the borders.
好吧 这画告诉了线索给他们
All right, this painting told them something.
我们得知道那是什么
We need to figure out what that is.
不好意思 久等了 西村先生
Sorry for the wait, Mr. Noshimuri,
转账现在完成了
but the transfer's now complete.
科诺
Kono.
大家都趴下
Everybody get down!
没事了 没事了
It's okay, it's okay.
叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
拜托了 他受伤了
Please, he needs help.
叫救护车
Somebody call an ambulance!
我们究竟要找什么
So what exactly are we supposed to be looking for?
我不知道 杰瑞
I don't know. Jerry?
这全部就是你们在船上找到的
This is everything from the boat?
是的 怎么了
Yeah, why?
天呐
Geez.
我怎能错过这呢 这个画框是不对的
How'd I miss this? This frame's wrong.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
看一下
Take a look. See?
画框不同
Different frames.
这画当初被偷走的时候
When the painting was originally stolen,
画框是铜制的 这个是木制
the frame was brass. This is wood.
所以海盗将它换了
Okay, so the pirates changed it.
那他们为什么要费这个劲呢
But why would they go through the trouble?
我认为找到宝藏的关键并不是画
I think the key to finding this treasure isn't the painting.
而是画框
It's the frame.
成 我需要画的图片
Chin, I need a picture of the painting.
尺寸大小一样的
Same size as the real thing.
小杰 你在干什么
What are you doing, Jer?
看 画框的每一条的后面
Take a look-- there's a notch
都有一个刻痕
on the back of each piece.
他说得没错
He's right.
仔细看了
Now pay attention.
每个角落都代表一个方向
Each corner represents a direction.
北 东 南 西
North, east, south, west.
谁要说出来
So who's gonna say it?
你来说
You should say it.
刻舟求到剑了
"X" Marks the spot.
我们准备搞定了
We're almost done.
赛门
Simon.
赛门 我找到了
Simon, I found it.
赛门
Simon.
Simon?
掩护
Cover!
就是它了
That's it, isn't it?
最好是纯金的
Those better be solid gold.
并不是
They're not.
我以为你说这堆值几百万呢
I thought you said this stuff was worth millions.
兄弟 我可以去城里的典当铺
Man, I can go down to aloha pawn,
把这些连这个箱子都买到
buy everything in here and the case
而且给20美元还有得找呢
and still get change back from a 20.
这就是传说故事嘛
That's the legend.
有可能海盗船长将宝藏给埋了当作诱饵
You know, maybe the captain buried this as a decoy.
真正的宝藏还在外面
The real treasure could still be out there.
好吧 如果真是这样的话
Yeah, well, if it is,
不少人白白牺牲了他们的生命了
a lot of people Lost their lives for nothing.
让我猜一下
Let me guess--
你们就只是找到些银器和几个蜡烛台
You found some silverware and a couple candlesticks.
是啊 你怎么知道的
Yeah, how'd you know that?
我查了一下宫廷档案
Went through the palace archive,
找到了沃什本的旧员工记录
found Washburn's old employee record.
他被解雇了
The dude was fired from the gig
是因为他被怀疑偷了银器
because he was suspected of stealing some silverware
和几个蜡烛台
and a couple candlesticks.
你震惊到人家了
I'm shocked.
好吧 其实并没有 杰瑞 他是名海盗
I'm not really shocked, Jerry, the guy was a pirate.
不 其实他不是 这是最扯淡的部分
No, He wasn't. That's the crazy part.
根据这文档 沃什本出生于1882年
According to this, Washburn was born in 1882.
也就说他对艾斯利谎报了年龄
which means he lied about his age to Exley.
那些海盗在暴戾恣睢的时候
When those pirates were doing their thing,
他还是小屁孩一枚
Washburn was still in diapers.
所以沃什本撒谎说他是海盗
So Washburn lied about being a pirate.
整件事就是一个大骗局
Whole thing was a giant hoax.
他确实是在宫廷干活
Well, hell, the guy did work at the palace.
我肯定他一定有
I'm sure he had some insider
宫廷历史那方面的内幕故事
knowledge as to the history of the place.
有可能他想可以加上海盗传说
Probably figured he could use that plus the pirate legend,
来给自己赚点钱
make himself some cash.
大家都喜欢海盗故事什么的
Everyone fell for it.
艾斯利 基努 我们
Exley, Keanu, us.
还有他的曾外孙女
His own great- granddaughter.
你在你的蜜月期打电话给我干什么呢
What are you doing, calling me on your honeymoon?
你还好吧
You okay?
他们有说什么吗
What are they saying?
还没有 他还在手术室里
Nothing, yet. He's still in surgery.
但是即使他撑过来了
But even if he pulls through,
加布里埃尔带着他的钱逃了
Gabriel got away with the money
那笔钱是用来从山口组那边赎回亚当的自由
that was meant to buy his freedom from the Yakuza.
没有那笔钱 我和他就没命了
Without it, we're both dead.